Register to The Quincy Porter Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Biographical & Analytical Notes, ?-1967; Series IV; 1 Box
  - Notes on Ukrainian Suite (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Notes on Symphonic Ode (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Suite in C Minor (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Harpsichord Concerto (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Notes on Viola Concerto (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Notes on Piano Sonata (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Notes on Sonata No. 2 for Violin and Piano (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Notes on Quintet for Oboe and Strings (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Analytical comments about Concerto Concertante, Symphony No. 1, Dance in 3-Time, 16-page booklet (Box 25, Folder 14)
- Classroom Materials, ?-1966; Series V; 3 Boxes
  Notes used by Porter as a student and/or teacher are arranged in this series. Also included here are term papers and projects submitted by his students.
  - Early Notebooks, V.A
    - Notebooks dating from Paris years, 3 items. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks dating from years of study under Ernest Bloch, 3 items. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Materials, V.B
    - Lecture notes for early classes, 1 item. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      [i.e. Cleveland Institute or New England Conservatory]
    - Lecture notes, counterpoint class, 1947-1950; 1 item. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Lecture notes, 1951-1952; 1 item. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Notes, String Quartet Analysis class, Yale (Box 26, Folder 6-8)
    - Examinations, 5 items. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Lists of grades, lists of assignments, notes on pupils (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Attendance sheets - Ensemble Classes (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Diagrams, analysis of Well-Tempered Clavier Books I & II, 7 items. (Box 27, Folder 12)
      (not complete)
    - Diagrams, analysis of Well-Tempered Clavier Books I & II, 10 items. (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Diagrams, analysis of Well-Tempered Clavier Books I & II, 7 items. (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Analytical diagrams & charts (Box 27, Folder 15-17, Box 28)
    - Student assignments & papers (Box 28, Folder 18-21)
- Published Articles and Books, 1936-1965; Series VI; 1 Box
  This series includes periodical articles as well as Porter's published theoretical writings. Materials have been placed into two categories: those written by Porter and those of other authorship.
  - Written by Porter, VI.A
    - Book review, 1936; 1 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Outline for the Study of Fugue Writing, pamphlet, 1 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Outline-Workbook for Fugue Writing, 1 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - "The Education of the American Composer," article in Musicology, vol. I, no. 1, 1945; 1 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - A Study of l6th-Century Counterpoint, 1st ed., 3 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - A Study of l6th-Century Counterpoint, 2nd ed., 1 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - A Study of l6th-Century Counterpoint, 3rd ed., 1 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Other, VI.B
    - "Charles Ives 1874-1954," article by Leo Schrade. Yale Review, summer 1955, 1 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - "The New Liberalism," article by Billy Jim Layton.Perspectives of New Music, vol. III, no.2 (spring/summer 1965), 1 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - "America in American Music," article by Philip Gordon. Common Ground, spring issue, 1947, 1 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Articles on stringed instruments (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - "On Improving Violins," by Frederick A. Saunders & Carleen M. Hutchins. Violins and Violinists Magazine, vol. 13, nos. 7/8, Nov-Dec 1952
      - "A Study of Tap Tones," by Hutchins, Hopping, Saunders. The Strad, Aug-Sep 1958
      - "Subharmonics and Plate Tap Tones in Violin Acoustics," by Hutchins, Hopping, Saunders. Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, vol. 32, no. 11, Nov 1960
      - "Violins Old and New: An Experimental Study," by F.A. Saunders. Sound, vol, 1, no. 4 Jul-Aug 1962
      - "The Physics of Violins," by Carleen Hutchins. Scientific American, Nov 1962
      - "Some Thoughts on the Requirements of a Good Varnish," by Robert E. Fryxell. The Strad, Feb 1965
- Photographs, 1922-1961; Series VII; 1 Box
  The main body of this small group of photographs concerns itself with associates of Porter during his Cleveland years. Also present are several scenes from the Music Hut, an endeavor and by-product of Porter's summer vacations.
  - Porter with Mr. and Mrs. Jean Binet, 1922; 3 items. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Scenes from Music Hut, 192-; 4 items. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Maurice Hewitt, 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Paul Fetler and family, 1949; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Yale Commencement, 1961; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Unidentifiable, 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - André de Ribaupierre, 1925; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Roger Sessions, 1925; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Medals, 1936, ?; Series VIII; 1 Box
  - Medal, presented by XIth Olympiade, Berlin, 1936; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Medal, unidentifiable, No date; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Scrapbooks, 1917-1966; Series IX; 7 Boxes
  These scrapbooks are full of many interesting items: clippings, programs, letters, other memorabilia. Please note that all correspondence contained in these scrapbooks has been photocopied and filed alphabetically within the correspondence series.
  The numbering of Scrapbooks is Porter's numbering.
  - Scrapbook/journal. Red Cross concerts (Box 31, Folder 1)
    (tour with Bruce Simonds)
  - Scrapbook, general (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook 1. Paris, 1931 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 2. Bad Homburg, 1931 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook 3. Cleveland, Ohio, 1931-1932 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook 4. Quartet, Cleveland, Vassar, 1931-1934 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, Yaddo, etc., 1933-1934 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook 5. Vassar, etc., 1935-1936 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook 6. Vassar, etc., 1936-1937 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook 7. New England Conservatory, 1937-1940 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook 7a. N.Y. Philharmonic concert, 1937-1943 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook 8. New England Conservatory, 1941-1943 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook 9. New England Conservatory (mostly), 1942-1943 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook 10. New England Conservatory, 1942-1946 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook, general, 1945-1951 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook, general, late '40s-1966 (Box 37, Folder 16)
- Porter's Works, 1914-1966; Series X; 24 Boxes
  Porter's works have been listed chronologically according to date of composition. Concluding the series are several folders of unidentified sketches as well as a set of index cards which contain information about the works, including dates of performance (notations made by Porter).
  For index cards containing data on Porter works, see folder 159.
  - Trio, for flute, violin, viola, [1914?]; pen & pencil sketch (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Early Pieces, 1914-1916 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    [all holographs, mostly violin and piano pieces]
    - No. 1: Melody in A Minor, Op. 1, No. 1
    - No. 2: violin and piano, Op. 1, No. 2
    - No. 3: Adagio, Op. 2, no. 1
    - No. 4: Op. 2, no. 2
    - No. 5: Op. 2, no. 3
    - No. 6: Op. 3, no. 1
    - No. 7: Op. 3, no. 2
    - No. 8: Op. 3, no. 3
    - No. 9: Grief, Op. 4
    - No. 10: Op. 6, no. 1
    - No. 11: Op. 6, no. 2
    - No. 12: Grief II
    - No. 13: Grief III, 1915 Apr 3
      insert: "Condemned as Bad Music," Sep 1914
    - Nos. 14 & 15: Shepherd's Lament and Dance of the Sprites, 1915 Jul 17
    - No. 16: April 4, 1915
    - No. 17
    - No. 18: Allegro molto vivace, Op. 8, no. 1
    - No. 19: Andante, 1915 Dec 23
    - No. 20: Jan 2, 1916
    - No. 21: Jan 2, 1916
    - No. 22: Winter, 1916
    - No. 23: April, 1916
    - No. 24: May, 1916
    - No. 25: June 28, 1916
    - Violin Part, Nos. 1-22
    - Allegro moderato, 1917 Jan
    - Song, 1918 Mar 26
      (text by Shelley)
    - Summer, 1918
    - Grazioso con moto
    - Quincy's waltz
    - Contresujets
    - A Mood
    - Counterpoint Exams, June 1917
    - A Hymn Tune
    - Manuscript, 8 pages - no identifying features
  - Pieces, 1917-1919; [all holographs] (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - 1. Andante, string quartet. Score, 1917
    - Duo, violin & viola. Score, 1917
    - Canon in the 7th, oboe & horn in F, with string quartet. Score, 1918
    - Fugue in G-sharp Minor, organ. Score, 1918; 2 copies
    - Theme and Variations in E Major, string quartet. Score & 7 parts, 1919
      (2nd set of parts lacking viola part)
      [mid-year exam in free composition]
    - Sonata, violin & piano. Score & part, 1919
  - Pieces, 1919-1923; [all holographs] (Box 38, Folder 4)
    sketches
    - Molto moderato, violin & piano. Score, 1919
    - Allegro appassionato, violin & piano. Sketch; score & part, 1919
    - Concerto, D major, violin & orchestra. Reduction for violin & piano. Score & part., 1920
    - Monodie Sans Parole, [violin?] written for D'Indy, 1920
    - Two Pieces, piano, 1921
    - Fugue Subjects & Countersubjects, written for Bloch, 1921
    - Three Practice Fugues, 1921
    - Minuetto & Adagio, piano. Written for Bloch, 1921
    - Manuscript, 3 pages
  - Concerto, violin & orchestra, lb: (Box 38, Folder 5-7)
    [written for graduation from Yale School of Music]
  - Pieces, 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Prelude, string quartet, 1923; holograph, score & 3 parts
      (lacking 1st violin part)
    - Prelude 2, string quartet, lb:
    - Boutade, piano, 1923; lb:
    - Nocturne, piano, 1923; 3 items; holographs, score
    - The Cloisters, piano, 1923; 2 items; holographs, score
    - Ukrainian Folk Songs, violin & piano, 2 items; holographs, score
    - Our Lady of Potchaiv (Ukrainian folksong) for string quartet, 1923; holograph score & parts
    - Scherzo, string quartet, 1923; holograph, score & parts
  - Songs, 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Notebooks containing sketches and holographs of "To the Moon" and "And, Like a Dying Lady", 2 items.
    - "To the Moon" [Shelley], 1922; holograph, score
    - "And, Like a Dying Lady" [Shelley], 1923; holograph, score
    - "And, Like a Dying Lady" [Shelley], 1923; holograph, score
      version for soprano & orchestra
    - "The Silent Voices" [Tennyson], 1924; holograph, score
    - "The Silent Voices" [Tennyson], 1924; 3 items; positive photocopies, another holograph score
    - "Music, When Soft Voices Die" [Shelley], 1924; holograph, score
    - Music Press, Inc. publication, 1947; 2 copies
  - String Quartet No. 1, E Minor, 1922-1923; bound holograph score & 1st violin part (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - String Quartet No. 1, E Minor, 1922-1923; unbound holograph score & 4 parts (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Go to Sleep (Negro Song), voice & piano, 1923; 3 holographs, score (Box 39, Folder 12)
    arrangement for baritone & string orchestra
    holograph, score
    multiple ink copies, voice & string parts
  - Sonata, violin & piano, No. 1, E Minor, 1925-1926; holograph, score & part (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Sonata, violin & piano, No. 1, E Minor, 1925-1926 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    positive photocopy of holograph score
    3 positive photocopies of holograph part
  - Sonata, violin & piano, No. 1, E Minor, 1925-1926; negative photocopy, holograph score & part (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Ukrainian Suite, string orchestra, 1925; positive photocopy of holograph score (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Ukrainian Suite, string orchestra, 1925; multiple photocopies of holograph parts (Box 40, Folder 17)
    [holographs of 2nd Violin, Viola, Bass parts]
  - Ukrainian Suite, string orchestra, 1927 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    C.C. Birchard publication. Score
  - Our Lady of Potchaiv (3rd movement of Ukrainian Suite), holograph, score (Box 40, Folder 19)
    multiple copies of parts (holographs and photocopies thereof)
  - Libretto for the Ukrainian National Chorus (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - String Quartet No. 2, 1925; holograph, score (Box 40, Folder 21)
    holograph, parts (incomplete)
  - String Quartet No. 2, 1925; positive photocopy of holograph score & parts (Box 40, Folder 22)
    [not above holograph]
    negative photocopy of holograph score & parts [same as positive copy]
  - Incidental Music to Midsummer Night's Dream, 1926; holograph, score & 4 parts (Box 40, Folder 23)
    [scored for woodwind quartet]
  - Incidental Music to Sunken Bell [piano], 1926; holograph, score (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Suite in C Minor, orchestra, 1926; holograph, score (Box 41, Folder 25)
    holograph, parts [complete, with multiple photocopies of string parts]
  - Suite in C Minor, orchestra, 1926; emph: not; lb: (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Suite in C Minor, orchestra, 1928 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    holograph, revised score
    positive photocopy of above
    negative photocopy of above
  - Suite in C Minor, orchestra. Arranged for piano, 2 or 4 hands, holograph, score (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Suite in C Minor, orchestra. Arranged for 2 pianos, lb: (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - In Monasterio, string quartet, 1927; lb: (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - In Monasterio, for small orchestra, holograph, score & parts (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Quintet, piano & strings, 1927; lb: (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - Quintet, piano & strings, 1927; 2nd holograph score & parts (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - Counterpoint, for string quartet, 1928; holograph, score & 3 parts (Box 42, Folder 34)
    [lacking viola part]
  - Suite in E Major, for flute, violin, viola, 1928; lb: (Box 42, Folder 35)
    copies made from transparencies, violin and viola parts
  - Little Trio, flute, violin, viola [originally titled Suite in E Major], 1962; lb: (Box 42, Folder 36)
    2 sets Valley Music Press publication, score & parts
  - Blues Lointains, flute & piano, 1928; lb: (Box 42, Folder 37)
  - Toccata, Andante & Finale, organ, 1929-1932; lb: (Box 42, Folder 38)
    copy made from transparencies, score
  - Hymn Tunes, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 39)
    copies of text
    ink copies of hymns [2]
  - Quintet, clarinet & strings, 1929; holograph, score & parts [marked "original score"] with clarinet part arranged for violin (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - Quintet, clarinet & strings, 1929; lb: (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Piece for Organ, 1929; holograph, score [with optional flute part] (Box 43, Folder 42)
  - Piece for Piano, 1929; holograph, score (Box 43, Folder 42)
  - Berceuse for Little Helen, for violin [flute] & piano, lb:; emph: not (Box 43, Folder 43)
  - Sonata, violin & piano, No. 2, 1929; lb: (Box 43, Folder 44)
    G. Schirmer publication for SPAM 1933
  - Sonata for Piano, 1930; lb:; emph: before (Box 43, Folder 45)
  - Sonata for Piano, 1930; lb: (Box 43, Folder 46)
    3 pages of last movement, typescript
  - Suite for Viola Alone, 1930; lb: (Box 43, Folder 47)
    Valley Music Press publication, score (3 items) 1946
    2 pages of negative photocopy of published version
  - String Quartet No. 3, 1930; lb: (Box 44, Folder 48)
    2 sets holograph, parts
  - String Quartet No. 3, 1930; lb: (Box 44, Folder 49)
    G. Schirmer publication for SPAM, score & 2 sets of parts 1935-1936
  - Twelve Songs for Helen, on Nursery Rhymes, 1931; lb: (Box 44, Folder 50)
    3 sets copies made from transparencies, score
  - Twelve Songs for Helen, on Nursery Rhymes orchestrated version [4 woodwinds & strings], 1955; lb: (Box 44, Folder 50)
  - String Quartet No. 4, 1931; holograph, score [in 3 volumes; 4th volume of sketches for 3rd movement] (Box 44, Folder 51)
    holograph, parts [extra set, 2nd movement only]
    2 sets positive photocopies, holograph parts
    positive photocopy, holograph score [not above holograph]
  - String Quartet No. 4, 1931; 2 sets (Box 44, Folder 52)
    Arrow Music Press publication, scores & parts [2nd set lacking viola part]
  - Two Moods, for orchestra, 1932; sketch book (Box 45, Folder 53)
  - Poem and Dance [originally titled "Two Moods"], 1932; lb: (Box 45, Folder 54)
    Poem and Dance check sheet
    holograph on transparencies, 1st violin part
    typescript on transparencies, parts
  - Poem and Dance [originally titled "Two Moods"] 1932, lb: (Box 45, Folder 55)
  - Poem and Dance, arranged for 2 pianos, holograph on transparencies, score (Box 45, Folder 56)
    2 copies made from transparencies, score
  - Music for Sweeney Agonistes [T.S. Eliot] and a series of Greek mimes translated by Philip H. Davis, 1933; holograph, score & parts [with extra ink copies of several sections] (Box 45, Folder 57)
    several pages of text
    memorial pamphlet for Philip H. Davis
  - Music for Sweeney Agonistes [T.S. Eliot] and a series of Greek mimes translated by Philip H. Davis, 1933; typescript on transparencies, score & parts (Box 45, Folder 58)
    2 sets copies made from transparencies, score & parts
  - Music for Antony and Cleopatra [Shakespeare], 1934; holograph, score & parts [with multiple photocopied string parts] (Box 46, Folder 59)
  - Music for Antony and Cleopatra [Shakespeare], 1934; cue cards (Box 46, Folder 60)
  - Excerpts from Antony & Cleopatra (Suite), 1937; lb: (Box 46, Folder 60)
  - Excerpts from Antony & Cleopatra (Suite), 1937; holograph, parts (Box 46, Folder 61)
  - Drinking Song from Antony and Cleopatra, for woodwind quartet, holograph, score (Box 46, Folder 61)
  - Symphony No. 1, 1934; lb: (Box 47, Folder 62)
  - Symphony No. 1, 1934; lb: (Box 47, Folder 63)
  - Symphony No. 1, arranged for 2 pianos, lb: (Box 47, Folder 64)
  - String Quartet No. 5, 1935; lb: (Box 48, Folder 65)
    ACA Composers Facsimile Edition publication, score
  - Piece for Piano, [1935?]; lb: (Box 48, Folder 66)
  - String Quartet No. 6, 1937; lb:; emph: not (Box 48, Folder 67)
  - String Quartet No. 6, 1937; lb: (Box 48, Folder 68)
  - String Quartet No. 6, 1937 (Box 48, Folder 69)
    2 sets G. Schirmer publication for SPAM, score & parts 1941-1942
  - Dance in 3-Time, for chamber orchestra, 1937; lb: (Box 49, Folder 70)
  - Dance in 3-Time, for chamber orchestra, 1937; emph: not; lb: (Box 49, Folder 71)
  - Dance in 3-Time, arranged for 2 pianos, lb: (Box 49, Folder 71)
  - Quintet, flute and strings, on a childhood theme, 1937; lb:; emph: Musicology (Box 49, Folder 72)
  - Music for Vassar Founder's Day Shows [words by Christine Ramsey, music by Porter and Clair Leonard], 1937; numerous pages of text (Box 49, Folder 73)
    Contents:
    Hormony
    It Must Be Something About Me
    Love Is Just What I Thought
    Heavenly Blues
    Maturity
    The Floraborealis Girls
    Cro'-n'est Waltz
    Give Me the Opportunity (part only)
    Heavenly Blues (part only)
    Fun in the Zoo (part only)
  - This Is the House That Jack Built, 1937 or 1938; lb: (Box 49, Folder 74)
  - This Is the House That Jack Built orchestrated version, 1955; lb: (Box 49, Folder 74)
  - Two Dances for Radio, in Four- and Five-Time, 1938 (Box 49, Folder 75)
    negative photocopy, holograph score
  - Lonesome, for Piano, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 76)
    Carl Fischer publication
  - Eight Pieces for Bill, 1941-1942; lb: (Box 49, Folder 77)
  - Pony Ride, for two pianos, 1941?; lb: (Box 49, Folder 77)
  - Piece for Violin, 1941?; holograph, score (Box 49, Folder 77)
  - Billiard Room Music, 1941?; holograph, score (Box 49, Folder 77)
  - Music for Strings, 1941; lb: (Box 50, Folder 78)
  - Music for Strings Music Press publication, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 79)
    2 scores
    parts
  - Fugue for String Quartet (or oboe & strings), 1941; lb: (Box 50, Folder 80)
  - Canon and Fugue, for organ, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 81)
    H.W. Gray publication, score 1944
  - Fantasy on a Pastoral Theme, organ and string orchestra, 1943; lb:; emph: not (Box 50, Folder 82)
  - String Quartet No. 7, lb: (Box 50, Folder 83)
  - String Quartet No. 7, lb: (Box 50, Folder 84)
  - String Quartet No. 7, lb: (Box 50, Folder 85)
    Valley Music Press publication 1944
    3 miniature scores, 3 sets parts
  - The Moving Tide, for orchestra, 1944; lb: (Box 51, Folder 86)
  - The Moving Tide, for orchestra, 1944; holograph, parts [with multiple copies of string parts, made from transparencies] (Box 51, Folder 87)
  - Four Pieces, violin and piano [Pastorale, Scherzando, Melody, Rondo], 1944-1947; lb: (Box 51, Folder 88)
  - Piece for Piano, 1946; holograph, score (Box 51, Folder 89)
  - Sonata, french horn & piano, 1946; lb: (Box 51, Folder 90)
    holograph page entitled "Chimes from Horn Sonata"
    typescript, horn part
    Gamble Hinged Music Co. publication, score & part [with extra horn part]
  - Sextet on [Soviet] Slavic Folk Songs, for strings, 1947; lb: (Box 51, Folder 91)
  - Sextet, arranged for new family of violins made by Carleen Hutchins, typescript on transparencies, parts (Box 51, Folder 91)
  - Two Fugues (Bach-like), 1947; holographs, scores (Box 51, Folder 92)
  - Wedding Prelude and March, 1948; lb: (Box 51, Folder 93)
  - Concerto for Viola and Orchestra, 1948; lb: (Box 52, Folder 94)
  - Concerto for Viola and Orchestra, 1948; lb: (Box 52, Folder 95)
  - Concerto for Viola and Orchestra, 1948; emph: not (Box 52, Folder 96)
  - Concerto for Viola and Orchestra version arranged for viola & piano, lb: (Box 52, Folder 97)
  - Concerto for Viola and Orchestra version arranged for viola & piano (Box 52, Folder 98)
    Associated Music Publishers publication, score & part 1948
  - (Juilliard) Pieces for Strings, 1948-1949
    - 1. Improvisation, for violin and piano, 1948; lb: (Box 52, Folder 99)
    - 2. Speed Etude, for viola and piano, 1948; lb: (Box 52, Folder 100)
    - 3. Poem, for cello (or viola) & piano, 1948; lb: (Box 52, Folder 101)
    - 3. Poem, for cello (or viola) & piano, 1948; typescript in final paste-up, score & parts (Box 52, Folder 102)
      2 items Valley Music Press publication, scores & parts 1957
    - 4. Lyric Piece [Poem] for Contrabass & Piano, 1949; lb: (Box 52, Folder 102)
    - 5. Bagatelle, string quintet, 1949; lb:; emph: not (Box 52, Folder 103)
  - Cantata for the Composers' Guild, 1949; lb: (Box 53, Folder 105)
  - Divertimento, 2 violins & viola (or oboe, violin, viola), 1949; lb: (Box 53, Folder 106)
  - Divertimento, 2 violins & viola, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 107)
    2 sets Valley Music Press publication, scores & parts 1949
  - Fugue in D Minor, 1949; lb: (Box 53, Folder 108)
  - The Desolate City, scena for baritone & orchestra, 1950; lb:; emph: not (Box 53, Folder 109)
  - The Desolate City, scena for baritone & orchestra, 1950; positive photocopies, holograph parts [originals not present] (Box 53, Folder 110)
  - String Quartet No. 8, 1950; lb: (Box 54, Folder 111)
  - String Quartet No. 8, 1950; lb: (Box 54, Folder 112)
    copies made from transparencies, parts
    2 sets Valley Music Press publication, scores & parts 1950
  - Incidental Music to Song For A Broken Horn, 1952; lb: (Box 54, Folder 113)
  - Concerto Concertante, 2 pianos & orchestra, 1953; emph: Promenade; lb: (Box 54, Folder 114)
  - Concerto Concertante, 2 pianos & orchestra, 1953; lb: (Box 54, Folder 115)
  - Promenade, for piano, 1953; 1956; lb: (Box 55, Folder 116)
  - Duo, violin & viola, 1954; pencil sketch (Box 55, Folder 117)
  - Duo, violin & viola 1. First version, 1952; lb: (Box 55, Folder 117)
  - Duo, violin & viola 2. Final version, 1954; lb: (Box 55, Folder 117)
    Valley Music Press publication, score & parts 1962
  - Incidental Music to The Merry Wives of Windsor, 1954; holograph, score & parts (Box 55, Folder 118)
  - Introspections on The Banks o'Doon, flute, voice, piano, 1955; 2 positive photocopies, holograph score (Box 55, Folder 119)
  - Songs, 1956
    typescript of both songs on transparencies, score
    3 copies made from transparencies, score
    - 1. Sonnet [Alan Porter], lb: (Box 55, Folder 120)
    - 2. Graveyard [Alan Porter], lb: (Box 55, Folder 120)
  - Music for a Film on Yale Library [later to become New England Episodes], 1956; lb: (Box 55, Folder 121)
  - Music for a Film on Yale Library [later to become New England Episodes], 1956; lb: (Box 55, Folder 122)
  - Nocturne, piano, 1956; lb: (Box 55, Folder 123)
  - Duo, viola & harp, 1957; lb: (Box 56, Folder 124)
    2 items Associated Music Publishers publication, score & part 1960